Hello, my friends.
An exercise number 71, we are asked to write a function that counts, then notes and circular link
at list post the video.
Think about it.
How to do that?
How to count that.
All of the notes that we are.
That it is contained in a circular ink list.
So I am waiting for your solution in the comments below.
Public static end and it is called Count Count notes.
It took into buried meter that had note that it is representing the head of the Lincoln list and we
start by making and you cursor that it is a new term.
This time people is referred to as had, so it is the same position at the TED.
And the end counter equal to zero, if we check if had does not equal to null, then we make do, why
do we need to move the cursor?
Temp equals temp dot next.
We have learned this and before before and increase that counter by one.
So counter + +.
OK, you see, guys, how we have make this, we have created an integer that counts and we move the
temp temp dot next.
We have moved.
Move that cursor to the next.
And notes to them that's not equal to their head and so and single link blessed we used now because
at the end we use them does not equal to now because at the last note it was referred to then not.
But here in a circular link, at least Attempt does not equal to had well means that we have reached
the end of that Lincoln list again.
So it's very simple to know we need to return the counter because we have created this method to return.
And let's see.
Let's test this method system that our good friend and.
And number of notes contained,
it will make we call the method count nodes, and we need to best the head in order to start counting
notes.
Let's run and see.
And here we have.
Five nodes, number of nodes contained is five.
So it's very simple.
We have seen this before, but the trick here in the count node become damp does not equal to hat and
not not that time.
Complexity of this function is oh of an OK because we are traversing through all their methods through
all the then nodes and the delete node.
Also, it is.
It is all of that OK because we are traversing through the node in the best in the best case scenario,
we delete the node that the first position at the end at the worst case scenario, adding the node.
At the end, and we are searching all the notes here.
Also, the count, not in the best case scenario, we have one note.
So it's off one and ending in the worst case scenario, we have a number of nodes, so we are going
to traverse through all of the on them and by adding that count there and traversing them.
So this loop where result in of and as worst case scenario for our.